Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
- Printed material, 1958-2003, Series 3; Boxes 74 – 88; OP10 – OP13
  - Reviews, 1966-2002, Subseries 3.3; Boxes 80 - 83
    - Field Work, 1979 [1 of 2] (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Field Work, 1979 [2 of 2] (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Poems, 1965-1975, 1980 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Preoccupations, 1980 [1 of 2] (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Preoccupations, 1980 [2 of 2] (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - An Open Letter, 1983 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Faber Poetry Cassettes, 1984 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Station Island, 1984 [1 of 4] (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Station Island, 1984 [2 of 4] (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Station Island, 1984 [3 of 4] (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Station Island, 1984 [4 of 4] (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Sweeney Astray, 1984 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - The Rattle Bag, 1985 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Haw Lantern, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - The Government of the Tongue, 1988 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Poems, 1966-1984, 1988 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Cure at Troy, theatre reviews, 1990s (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - New Selected Poems, 1966-1987, 1990 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Seeing Things, 1991 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Sweeney's Flight, 1992 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - The Redress of Poetry, 1995 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Homage to Robert Frost, 1996 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Laments by Jan Kochanowski, translated by Stanislaw Baranczak and Seamus Heaney, 1996 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Spirit Level, 1996 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Beowulf, 2000 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Electric Light, 2001 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Finders Keepers, 2002 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - General review articles, various dates (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Collected printed materials, 1958-2003, Subseries 3.4; Boxes 84 – 88; OP13
    The collected printed materials consist of a variety of materials collected by Seamus Heaney from 1958-2003, including poems, essays, chapbooks, galley proofs, and offprints of other writers. Also present are a small collection of periodicals and a larger group of programs collected by Heaney.
    - Writings of others
    - Anonymous, "Caoineadh na Maighdine," musical score (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Abbs, Peter, "Samizdat Stanzas," poem sheet, 1993 with note from the author (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Alcorn, Alfred, "In the Kingdom of Nabokovia," Harvard Review, proof, undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Antonaides, Anthony C., Poetics of Architecture, Theory of Design, Chapter 6: "Poetry and Literature," photocopy (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Astor, Brooks, "Discipline," poem card, inscribed and signed by author (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Balakian, Peter, "A Christmas Message from Frank Lloyd Wright," poetry card, 1989 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Baranczak, Stanislaw, "Petit-Bourgeois Virtues," with nine other poems, typescript with notes in Seamus Heaney's hand (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Beach, Christopher, "Who Else Has Lived Through Purgatory?": Ezra Pound and Robert Lowell," offprint (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Beckett, Samuel, translator, Anthology of Mexican Poetry, Indiana University Press, 1958, photocopy (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Bosch, Daniel, Homages & Elegies, Chapbook with holograph note laid in, signed 1998 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Braidwood, J., "Terms for 'Left-handed' in the Ulster Dialects," offprint from Ulster Folklife, volume 18, 1972, inscribed (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Christmas, John, "Inishbofin," final draft, 2003, with letter from the author (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Cook, Eleanor, "'A Seeing and Unseeing in the Eye': Canadian Literature and Sense of Place," offprint from Daedalus, Fall, 1988 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Davitt, Michael, Two poems in Innti 10, inscribed and signed by the author, 1986 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Dawe, Gerald, "Telling a Story: Beyond Across a Roaring Hill: the Protestant Imagination in Modern Ireland," offprint from Studies, Summer 1988, signed (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - Dodge, Jim, "Practice, Practice, Practice," poem card, 1998 (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Dunn, Douglas, "'Importantly Live': Lyricism in Contemporary Poetry," Dundee University Occasional Papers 1, 1888, with letter from Hilda D. Speer laid in (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - Durkan, Teresita, "To a Migratory Bird," chapbook, inscribed and signed by author, 1989 (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - Emmott, Stuart Earle, "Particles of Rain," chapbook, 1985 (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Engel, Moore, "An Exemplary Edmund Wilson," offprint from The Yale Review, 1987, inscribed by the author (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - Fanger, Donald, "Conflicting Imperatives in the Case of the Russian Writer: The Case of Tertz/Sinyavsky," offprint from Literature and History: Theoretical Problems and Russian Case Studies, 1986, inscribed (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - Foster, John Wilson, "A Redefinition of Topographical Poetry," offprint from Journal of English and Germanic Philology, volume 69, number 3, July 1970 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Foster, John Wilson, "A Runagate Tongue, Or, English as We Speak It in Ulster," galley proofs with holograph notes (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Gatton, John Spalding, "The Sunflower Saint: Oscar Wilde in Louisville," The Filson Club History Quarterly, volume 52, number 1, January 1978, photocopy (Box 84, Folder 24)
    - Gioia, Dana, "Poetry Chronicle," offprint, The Hudson Review, volume 34, number 4, Winter 1981-82, inscribed by the author (Box 84, Folder 25)
    - Greacen, Robert, "Some Memories of Michael McLaverty (1904-1992)," photocopied from unknown source with note from the author (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - Griffiths, Jane, "The House," chapbook, 1989 (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - Guenther, Charles, Poems and reviews from various sources, 1979-1998, photocopies (Box 84, Folder 28)
    - Howes, Barbara, "Being Me," poem card, Christmas 1982, signed (Box 84, Folder 29)
    - "The Iain Chrichton Smith Memorial Prize 1999," anthology of creative writing by Oban High School students (Box 84, Folder 30)
    - Johnston, Carol Ann, Eudora Welty: A Study of the Short Fiction, Twayne Publishers, 1997, photocopy (Box 84, Folder 31)
    - Jory, Jon, Commencement address, Bellarmine College, 14 May 1994 (Box 84, Folder 32)
    - Kane, George, "Poets and Poetics of Sin," The Morton W. Bloomfield Lectures on Medieval English Literature, I, Harvard University, 1989 (Box 84, Folder 33)
    - Kelly, Hannah, "The Struggle," poem cycle, 1982 (Box 84, Folder 34)
    - Langland, Joseph, "A Dream of Love," and "In Saarinen's Lake, poems signed by author, with letter and envelope, ca. 1980s (Box 84, Folder 35)
    - Lee, John Robert, "Clearing Ground: Poems," inscribed and signed by the author, Easter 1991 (Box 84, Folder 35)
    - Little, Graham, "The Flag My Father Wore," typescript for Eureka Street, June 1992 (Box 84, Folder 37)
    - Mackle, Henry, "Fairies and Leprechauns," photocopied from Ulster Life, volume 10, 1964, inscribed and signed by author (Box 84, Folder 38)
    - McGovern, Iggy, "Magdalen Sonnets," Ten sonnets, ca. 1999, signed by the author (Box 84, Folder 39)
    - Manson, John, "East Sutherland and Other Poems," "1985; Malevich in Edinburgh," 1977, chapbooks (Box 84, Folder 40)
    - Matthew, H.C.G., "Leslie Stephen and the New Dictionary of National Biography," Leslie Stephen Lecture, Cambridge University, 1995 (Box 84, Folder 41)
    - Montague, John, "Last Chance," Christmas broadside, second series, number ten, University Libraries, State University of New York at Buffalo, undated (Box 84, Folder 42)
    - Morisco, Gabriella, "The Painful Path of Voluntary Memory" the Art of Elizabeth Bishop," English Department, University of Hull, Occasional Paper 16, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 43)
    - Murphy, Hayden, " Broadsheet 1967-1978: Poetry, Prose, and Graphics," exhibition catalog, National Library of Scotland, 1983 (Box 84, Folder 44)
    - Murphy, Hayden, "5 ½" Bloomsday 2000, six poem cards with letter and envelope, 16 June 2000 (Box 84, Folder 45)
    - Murphy, Hayden, "Bloomsday Message, 2002" signed by the author, number 19 0f 50 with unpublished review of Collected Poems and obituary of Michael Hartnett (Box 84, Folder 46)
    - Narita, Tatsushi, "Eliot and His First Beating of the 'Bhghong' – A Brief Treatise on His View of Poetry," offprint from Studies in Social Sciences and Humanities, volume 32, March 1988 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Narita, Tatsushi, "T.S. Eliot and His St. Louis Area Background," offprint from Studies in Social Sciences and Humanities, volume 33, March 1989 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - O'Brien, Connor Cruise, articles on various topics, 1990 photocopies (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, "The Story of Potts' Tavern," photocopied from unknown source, signed by author, 1987 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, Gearoid, Wm. Colm Nolan and Paul Hoare, "Athlone Poets," poem sheet 1, Kincora Poetry, 1974, signed by the authors (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - O'Connor, Mike, translator, "Colors of Daybreak and Dusk: A Selection of Poems by Chia Tao (779-843)," 1995 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - O'Donoghue, Bernard, "Visiting the Birthplace of Aodhagan O Rathaille," proofs with holograph note written by author (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - O'Hayer, Patrick, "Border Wars," chapbook, inscribed and signed by author (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - O hlnneirghe, Seamas, "Uiliseas: a chum James Joyce," undated (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Pheathan, Ellen, Fifty Contemporary Poetry Books, 1998, with letter (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Printz-Pahlson, Goran, "Interview with Raymond Williams (1967)," offprint from Comparative Criticism, volume II, inscribed by author (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Rauchbauer, Otto, editor, "An Introductory Sketch", Ancestral Voices: The Big House in Anglo-Irish Literature, offprint, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Ruark, Gibbons, Rescue the Perishing, advance uncorrected proofs, 1991 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Rurak, Gibbons, "Spending an Irish Sixpence," photocopied from unknown source, inscribed to Heaneys, May 2002 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Rynne, Etienne, "Athenry, A Medieval Irish Town," inscribed and signed by author, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Sands, Bobby, The Diary of Bobby Sands, the first seventeen days of Bobby's H-Block hunger strike to the death, 1981 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Schuchard, Ronald, "'As Regarding Rhythm:' Yeats and the Imagists," photocopied from Yeats: An Annual of Critical and Textual Studies, volume II, 1984, inscribed and signed by author (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Shell, Marc, "OK; or Handel with Care," offprint from Common Knowledge, volume 3, Winter 1997, inscribed by author (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Stack, Tom, No Earthly Estate: The Religious Poetry of Patrick Kavanagh, galley proofs, pp. 1-99 [1 of 3] (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Stack, Tom, No Earthly Estate: The Religious Poetry of Patrick Kavanagh, galley proofs, pp. 100-173 [2 of 3] (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - Stack, Tom, No Earthly Estate: The Religious Poetry of Patrick Kavanagh, galley proofs, pp. 108-221 [3 of 3] (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - Sund, Robert, "Home: A Prayer for the World Where You Found It," poem card, 1988 (Box 85, Folder 22)
    - Thompson, E.P., "Education and Experience," Fifth Mansbridge Memorial Lecture, Leeds University, 1967, photocopy (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - Toraiwa, Masazumi, Five Elements, photocopied poetry collection, undated (Box 85, Folder 24)
    - Toraiwa, Masazumi, "Sayonara," poem card, undated (Box 85, Folder 25)
    - "Travels," Christmas card signed by Dorothea and Gerald, 1988 (Box 85, Folder 26)
    - Van de Waarsenburg, Hans, "Zuidwal (South Wall)", inscribed and signed by author, 1993 (Box 85, Folder 27)
    - Vierek, Peter, "Anti-Form or Neo: A Curse on Both Houses," photocopied from Parnassus Magazine, Spring, 1993 (Box 85, Folder 28)
    - Warren, Rosanna, review of Beyond Amazement: New Essays on John Ashbery, David Lehman, editor, 1980, offprint (Box 85, Folder 29)
    - Wathen, Ronnie, "Greek Discoteque," poem, signed by author, 1987 (Box 85, Folder 30)
    - Wilkinson, Paul and Griselda Cann Mussett, "Beowulf in Kent," Faversham Paper number 64, signed by Mussett, 1998 (Box 85, Folder 31)
    - Wormald, Mark, "Stills and Reflections," chapbook, Christmas 1988 (Box 85, Folder 32)
    - Periodicals
    - The Dublin Magazine, volume 8, numbers 1&2, Spring/Summer 1969 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Encounter, March and May 1963 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Envoy, Fall/Winter 1981-1982; Spring/Summer 1982; number 46, 1985 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Fortnight: An Independent Review for Northern Ireland, numbers 29, [30?], 36, 39, 40-41, 44, 50, 1971-1972 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - In-Between: Essays and Studies in Literary Criticism, volume 10, number 862, 2001 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Ireland of the Welcomes, volume 19, Spring 1971; volume 20, number 6, March-April 1972; volume 24, number 6, November-December 1975; volume 26, number 2, March-April 1977 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Landfall, volume 15, number 4, December 1961 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - The New Yorker, 16 March 1981; 15 September 1986 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - The New Yorker, 28 December 1987; 14 January 2002; 14 April 2003 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - NPFO 6 [ New Poetry from Oxford 6], 1988 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Pennypaper, no. 1, ca. 1960s (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Punch, 5 January 1977 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Tandem, 4/5, [1996] (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Programs
    - "The Cheviot, the Sly, and the Black Black Oil," by John McGrath, Abbey Theatre, June 1974 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Alexander Stone Lectureship in Bibliography (University of Glasgow), 1980-1987 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Recital by Charles Lynch to mark the bi-centenary of the birth of John Field, National Concert Hall (Dublin), 26 July 1982 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Eighty-fifth Annual Dinner of the American Irish Historical Society, The Waldorf-Astoria Hotel (New York), 1982 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - "Boseman and Lena," by Athol Fugard, Field Day Theatre Company 1983 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Eighty-sixth Annual Dinner of the American Irish Historical Society, The Waldorf-Astoria Hotel (New York), 1983 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Requiem mass for Robert Stuart Fitzgerald, St. Mary's Church (New Haven, Connecticut), 19 January 1985 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - The Charitable Irish Society, 248th Anniversary Dinner (Boston), 17 March 1985 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - "Double Cross," by Thomas Kilroy, Field Day Theatre Company, ca. 1986 with reviews laid in (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Dedication of the John J. Burns Library of Rare Books and Special Collections (Boston College), 22 April 1986 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - "Foundation Day," Harvard University, 4 September 1986 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Programs for honorary doctorate awards ceremonies, 1986-2002 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - The Charitable Irish Society, 250th Anniversary Dinner (Boston), 17 March 1987 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - A Memorial Tribute to Morton Wilfred Bloomfield, Harvard University, 26 May 1987 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - "Making History," by Brian Friel, Field Day Theatre Company, 1988 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Program in celebration of the life of Henry Kaiser, Washington, D.C., 17 May 1989 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - Magdalen College Chapel, Michaelmas Term (Oxford), 1991 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - The MacDiarmid Centenary in Langholm (Scotland), 13 September 1992 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Literary Exercises, Sanders Theatre, Harvard University, 8 June 1993 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Requiem mass to celebrate the life of Oisin Ferran, St. Brigid's Church, 22 December 1993 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - "Who Shall Be Happy..?" by Trevor Griffiths, Mad Cow Productions (Belfast), ca. mid 1990s (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - David Jones (1895-1970) Centenary Conference, University of Wales Department of English, 22-24 September 1995, with catalog of books by David Jones (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - "Six Characters in Search of an Author," by Luigi Pirandello, new version by Thomas Kilroy, The Abbey Theatre, 1996 (Box 87, Folder 25)
    - "Give Me Your Answer, Do!" by Brian Friel, Abbey Theatre, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 26)
    - "Substance and Shadow," Sixth John Hewitt International Summer School, St. MacNissi's College (Northern Ireland), 23-31 July 1993 (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - Synge Summer School, Rathdrum, County Wicklow, Ireland), 2-8 July 2000 (Box 87, Folder 28)
    - Requiem mass for Fr. Herbert McCabe, Priory of the Holy Spirit (Oxford), 5 July 2001 (Box 87, Folder 29)
    - London Jazz Festival, 9-18 November 2001 (Box 87, Folder 30)
    - Dixon/Bruce wedding, Holy Trinity Abbey Church (Adare, County Limerick), 16 February 2002 (Box 87, Folder 31)
    - "The Homecoming," Harold Pinter, Circle Theatre (Belfast), undated (Box 87, Folder 32)
    - "The Midnight Court," Druid Theatre Company, undated (Box 87, Folder 33)
    - "Travesties," Royal Shakespeare Company (London), undated (Box 87, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous programs, various dates (Box 87, Folder 35)
    - Other collected printed materials
    - Broadsheet series from Bernard Stone, Turret Books [1 of 2] (Box 87, Folder 36)
    - Broadsheet series from Bernard Stone, Turret Books [2 of 2] (Box 87, Folder 37)
    - Brochures/leaflets (Box 87, Folder 38)
    - Cartoons (Box 87, Folder 39)
    - Book catalogs (Box 87, Folder 40)
    - Exhibition catalogs (Box 87, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous catalogs (Box 87, Folder 42)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous topics [1 of 4] (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous topics [2 of 4] (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous topics [3 of 4] (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous topics [4 of 4] (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Flyers (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Newsletters, various issues of miscellaneous titles (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Pamphlets (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Posters (W.H. Auden) (Box OP13)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 88, Folder 8)
- Subject files, 1973-2003, Series 4; Boxes 89
  Subject files include miscellaneous files regarding trips Heaney took for readings, conferences, and awards and files relating to organizations in which he held membership and subjects that interested him and related to his writings. The series was created to accommodate these files which were not originally placed in a subject file arrangement.
  - Aosdana (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Arvon Foundation (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - The Atlantic Foundation (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Bogs (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Bologna trip, December 1993 [Seamus Heaney on "The Work of Poetry: Personal Reflections"] (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, miscellaneous radio scripts (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Common Wealth Awards (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Emory University visit, September 2003 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - European Academy of Poetry (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - International Poetry Festival, 1973 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Irish Literature Anthology (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Japan reading, 1987 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Kelleher, John V. (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Krakow Festival 2000 [2nd Meeting of Poets in Krakow, Poetry-Between Song and Prayer, 10-13 November 2000] (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Kyoto Conference, International Association for the Study of Anglo-Irish Literature, July 1990 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Lannan Foundation readings, October 1991 (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - Newdigate Prize for English Verse (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Princeton University, Program in Hellenic Studies [Heaney visit, 16 April 2000] (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Silkeborg Museum [Seamus Heaney's opening of the exhibition, "Face to Face with Your Past," 2 August 1996] (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Sutton Hoo [Seamus Heaney's address at the National Trust Museum, 13 March 2002] (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - The Sweeney bequest (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - University of California at Berkeley, poetry packet for Heaney's course "English IB," Fall 1970 (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - University of California at Berkeley [Seamus Heaney reading], 25 February 1999 (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - University of Coruna [Seamus Heaney's award, Doctor Honoris Causa, 2000] (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - University of Exeter [Seamus Heaney's award, honorary Doctor of Letters, 13 June 2001] (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - University of Las Vegas [Seamus Heaney visit, 18-20 February 1999] (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - University of Michigan [Seamus Heaney trip, 13-17 November 1999] (Box 89, Folder 27)
- Photographs, 1951-2003, Series 5; Boxes 90 – 93; OP1
  The series consists of photographs dating from 1951-2003 and include both amateur snapshots and professionally produced images, some in color and others in black and white. There are photographs of Seamus Heaney, photographs of Heaney with other individuals, other individuals and groups, objects, places, and other miscellaneous photographs from 1951-2003. The photographs of Heaney include portraits in academic regalia, publicity photographs, and a small number by Rollie McKeena. The snapshots were sent to Heaney primarily by acquaintances. The photographs of Heaney with other individuals (1958-2003) comprise the largest group and include many colleagues and friends, notably Derek Mahon, Michael Longley, Ted Hughes, Paul Muldoon, Brian Friel, Seamus Deane, Derek Walcott, Philip Hobsbaum and Joseph Brodsky. Many are snapshots, and a small number include family members. The series also includes a group of photographs of other individuals and a small number of photographs of objects and places.
  Arranged in subject groupings.
  - Seamus Heaney
  - Seamus Heaney sitting in grass, photographer: Jack McManus for The Irish Times, black and white, ca. 1960s (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Seamus Heaney standing in front of brick wall, photographer: James P. Fay, black and white, ca. 1960s (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Seamus Heaney graduation portrait from Queens University Belfast, photographer: Ashleigh Studios (Belfast), black and white, 18 July 1961 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Seamus Heaney standing beside large tree in cemetery, Belfast, photographer: Rollie McKenna, black and white, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Seamus Heaney, Belfast, photographer: Rollie McKenna, black and white, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Seamus Heaney at early book signing, photographer: Frances Charteris (London), black and white, ca. late 1960s (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Seamus Heaney publicity photograph for Faber & Faber (London), black and white, ca. 1970s (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Seamus Heaney, photographer: LaVerne H. Clark (Tucson, Arizona), seven black and white snapshots, ca. 1970s (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Seamus Heaney holding cigarette, black and white, ca. 1970s (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Seamus Heaney reading from North in the open air, Kilkenny [Rothe House?], black and white, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Seamus Heaney, publicity photograph by Layle Silbert (New York), black and white, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Seamus Heaney at desk, black and white, ca. 1980s (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Seamus Heaney, photographer: Gunnie Moberg (Stromness-Orkney), black and white, ca. 1980s (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Seamus Heaney leaning on walking stick in front of stone wall, black and white, ca. 1980s (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Seamus Heaney, Faber & Faber publicity photograph by Caroline Forbes, black and white, ca. 1980s (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Seamus Heaney reclining in leather chair, black and white, 1980s (Box 90, Folder 16)
  - Seamus Heaney at desk, photographer: Francene Keery, black and white, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 17)
  - Seamus Heaney, poetry seminar at St. Mary's College (Bay Area, California), two color snapshots, 1984 (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Seamus Heaney, photographer: Helen O'Shea, color snapshot, ca. 1984 (Box 90, Folder 19)
  - Seamus Heaney at Framington State College reception, color snapshot, ca. 1985 (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - Seamus Heaney standing before microphones in Moscow, black and white, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 21)
  - Seamus Heaney, trip to Australia, four black and white snapshots, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 22)
  - Seamus Heaney reading at the Varsity Theatre, photographer: Patrick Murphy-Racey, black and white, March 1988 (Box 90, Folder 23)